# TIM BEATSON

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A highly motivated DevOps Engineer keen to embrace a new challenge. Knowledge and handson experience of DevOps and Configuration Management of Windows and Linux environments. As part of an agile project, able to implement fully automated CI/CD pipelines as well as automated infrastructure.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

**Languages:** Bash, Ruby, Java, Shell scripting, Groovy **Version Control Systems:** Github, Bitbucket, Gitlab

Automation/Build Tools: Jenkins, Puppet, Terraform, Packer

Containerisation: Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, Kops App and Web Servers: Apache, NGINX, Tomcat, IIS

Databases: MySQL/MariaDB, MS SQL, Postgres, MongoDB

Virtualisation: SmartBear

Platforms: Ubuntu, Centos, Windows Server 2012 Network/Infrastructure: TCP/IP, DNS, DHCP

**Security Clearance:** SC cleared

#### **PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES**

- Passionate about engaging with new technologies to deliver innovation
- Confident self-teacher, driven to see tasks through to completion with minimal supervision
- Motivated and able to inspire others
- Personable and approachable attitude
- Ability to communicate and present ideas to all levels of an organisation

## **CAREER HISTORY**

# MONEYSUPERMARKET FINANCIAL GROUP PLC DevOps Core

## **DevOps Engineer** – 2018 – Present

DevOps Core work to support DevOps Engineers embedded within development squads as well as maintaining our AWS cloud platform.

- Ongoing migration of existing, Rightscale provisioned cloud platform to Kubernetes
- Producing Helm charts for deploying existing services to Kubernetes
- Implemented Prometheus monitoring of Kubernetes
- Optimised existing Docker images
- Scripted the migration of all Jenkins Mesos slaves to Kubernetes
- Enhanced visibility of environment builds
- Delivered Vault to Kubernetes
- Out of hours, on-call support

**Environment:** Kubernetes, Docker, Helm, Kops, Jenkins, JobDSL, Terraform, Packer, Vault, Ruby, Bash, Groovy, Puppet, AWS, Github, Bitbucket, NGINX, Traefik, Istio, Prometheus,

Grafana, Ubuntu, Centos, Sensu, Logspout, Loggly, Java

# CAPGEMINI UK PLC Test and Release Services (T&RS)

## Platform Engineer – 2016 – 2018

Part of a small DevOps team responsible for building and supporting a Cloud based solution which provides the core functionality of T&RS.

- Developed continuous integration pipeline to stand up platform on demand
- Working closely with architecture and test
- Follow code management process
- Responsible for knowledge transfer to rest of team
- Configured monitoring as part of live support
- Showcasing capabilities to current and potential clients
- Seek opportunities to add value by upgrading current tools and processes

**Environment:** Puppet, Terraform, Jenkins, Gitlab, Azure, CentOS, Windows Server 2012, Apache, IIS, MS SQL, MySQL, PowerShell, Bash, Syslog, ClamAV, ELK, Documentation, Infrastructure as Code

## **BRITISH ARMY**

**Sapper - 2014 – 2016** 

As a section sapper, developed a strong work ethic and sense of camaraderie whilst abiding by the armies core values of courage, discipline, respect for others, integrity, loyalty selfless commitment.

## STROMA CERTIFICATION

## **Technical Supervisor** - 2009 – 2014

Supervised a helpdesk for telephone and email support to Domestic Energy Assessors as well as conducting quality assurance audits of clients.

- Supported Stroma's bespoke software used to produce Energy Performance Certificates on domestic properties
- Ensured support gueries were answered in line with SLA
- Provided guidance to helpdesk operators to deliver advice accurately and with confidence
- Worked closely with developers to enable timely resolution of defects

## ZENOS IT ACADEMY

## Advanced Apprentice – 2008

The Zenos scheme was an advanced apprenticeship aiming to provide participants with several industry specific qualifications whilst simulating the experience of being in a workplace.

# **QUALIFICATIONS**

ISTQB Foundation & Agile Software Tester Microsoft Certified Desktop Support Technician CompTIA A+ City & Guilds Advanced Diploma for IT Practitioners NVQ Level 3 IT Professional

# **REFERENCES**

Available on request.